啊！又一个废弃的矿井？！
Ah!? Another abandoned mine?!
随我来 红蜘蛛
Come, Starscream.
我的君王 谁能预料到我那超级战士实验会遭遇…
My liege, who could have foreseen that my alternative super-soldier experiment would encounter...
技术性难题呢？
The technical difficulties?
赔上了全部昆虫大军和我们半数以上的部队吗？！
Resulting in the loss of the insecticon hive and over half our remaining troops!
请原谅我 主人！小人一片忠心 苍天可见！
Forgive me, Master! My intentions were true!
求求您！小的再次给您磕头了！
Please! Please reconsider my termination!
哦 原来这是震荡波的秘密实验室啊
Oh, Shockwave's offsite laboratory.
地方不错嘛
Most impressive.
巨狰狞的克隆进展已经接近尾声
The Predacon clones have almost fully evolved
预计将在三个太阳周期内完成战备
and will be combat-ready within three solar cycles.
干得好！震荡波
Well done! Shockwave.
击倒！我在等你
Knockout! I'm waiting.
马上就到 威震天陛下
On my way. Lord Megatron!
合成能量…士兵们将会把剩下的库存送过来
Synthetic Energon... troops will be delivering my remaining supply to you.
等威震天陛下的巨狰狞大军部署准备完毕\N我会来评估其价值的
I will determine its value after Lord Megatron's Predacon army is ready for deployment.
没规矩的畜生！你竟敢未经许可随处乱逛？
Unruly beast! You dare to roam freely without permission?
啊！呃！
Aaah! Eh!
啊！！！
Aaaah!!!
什么？！
What!?
再碰我一次！我就把那棍子插进你的火种里
Strike me again! And I will bury that rod in your spark.
我…我没想到野兽居然也能变形
I... I did not realize that the beast was capable of transformation.
我也很意外呢！
Nor did I!
我不是野兽！
I am no beast!
啊！
Aah!
变形能力是塞博特恩人的基本生理功能
The ability to transform is a fundamental part of Cybertronian biology.
但我们手中缺乏依据 去证明巨狰狞种群已进化至那个阶段
We simply posses no evidence that the Predacon species ever reached that evolutionary stage
鉴于他们在大灾变中已经灭绝
since they became extinct in the great cataclysm.
现在我们知道了…啊…
And now we know... Ah...
如此说来…传言是真的
So... the rumors are true.
我也不再孤单了
I would no longer be alone.
原来你一直有所隐瞒啊
And I see you've been keeping secrets.
我并非有意欺骗您 威震天陛下
It was not my intention to deceive you, Lord Megatron.
我也是最近才发现自己的这种能力
I only recently became aware of my abilities.
但我本身的记忆只有猎杀…
All I remember of my beginning is hunting...
…和战斗…
and battling...
…以及被人羞辱
and the wounding of my pride.
于是我便产生了疑问…
Thus I'd begun to burn with questions...
我是谁？
Who am I?
我从哪里来？
Where did I come from?
战舰上的数据库提供了一些史实依据
The warship's data banks provide historical fact
但是对于我的过去 我依然一无所知
but, still, I possessed no memory of my own past
于是我开始重新审视自己…
so I began to reconsider my place in the present...
更想知道“我是否也像其他人一样？”
and wondered "could I be like the others?"
而现在我知道了
And now I know.
你的确是个独一无二的科学奇迹
Yet you are unique, a miracle of science
是震荡波从提取的C.N.A.中克隆出来的
cloned by Shockwave from cybernucleic acid
从你那强大的祖先遗物中重生的奇迹
recovered from the remains of your mighty ancestors.
医生 你的合成能量研究目前进展如何？
Doctor, what is the current status of your Synthetic Energon experiments?
我一直在竭尽全力 指挥官
Doing the best I can, Commander.
哪怕是我缺乏趁手的设备
Given the lack of functional equipment at my disposal.
你应该明白替代能源对我们的生存至关重要吧？
You do realize that an alternative energy source may be essential to our survival?
呵…请相信我 通天晓
Heh... Believe me, Ultra Magnus.
没人能比我更了解这其中的利害关系
No one is more acutely aware of the stakes than I am.
呃…这是当然
Uhm... Of cause.
野兽猎人们 我想知道你们现在\N为什么不在305区域搜索巨狰狞骸骨？
Beast Hunters, may I ask why you are not currently scouting grid 305 for Predacon bones?
因为我们刚刚从301至304区域返回
Because we just returned from surveying grids 301 to 304.
以便根据您的规定去记录我们的实地报告\N通天晓指挥官 长官
To log our field reports, per your protocol, Commander Magnus, Sir.
士兵 我不记得批准过你离开基地
Soldier, I don't recall giving you permission to leave the base.
你的确没批准 长官
Because you didn't, Sir.
那为什么你的双手沾满冷却剂？
Why are your hands smeared with coolant?
我…我重新校准了你的飞船引擎
I... recalibrated your ship's engines.
你可以体验下矢量推力提升一成的感受了
You can expect a 10% increase in vector thrust.
- 欢迎回家！\N- 擎天柱！
- Welcome back!\N- Optimus.
- 见到你真高兴！\N- 你回来真是太好了 擎天柱！
- Good to see you!\N- It's good to have you back, Optimus.
霸天虎没有活动迹象
Decepticon activity is at a lull.
因此 我担心威震天已经收齐了他想要的样本…
I fear that Megatron may have collected the specimens he requires to...
…来克隆他的军队
clone his army.
对您的再生之恩 我无以为报…
It is with deepest gratitude for my creation...
从今往后 定当效犬马之劳
that I pledge undying obedience to you.
我唯一的真正的主人
My one true master.
而考虑到我的种群在队伍中不断快速壮大
But with more of my species soon to stride among us
我请求您能允许我 作为冲云霄
I beg your permission to in turn, lead them
…来领导他们
as Predaking.
你倒是目光远大啊
Your vision is boundless.
这只曾经的野兽 或许眼下甘为奴仆
A former beast may fully believe himself to be a loyal servant today
但相信我 当有一天 我们这位王子殿下
but trust me, the moment our royal highness...
…发现他手下军队的战斗力已经能够…
realize that his army possesses greater might...
…凌驾于霸天虎残余部队之上时…
than what currently remains of the Decepticons.
进化…必将导致变革
Evolution... will give way to revolution.
我已别无选择…
I am left with no choice...
…只能在克隆巨狰狞造反之前根除他们
but to eradicate the Predacon clones before they are provided the opportunity to eradicate us.
威震天陛下 您不会是说要终止震荡波心爱的巨狰狞计划吧？
Lord Megatron, you're not saying you intend to pull the plug on Shockwave's beloved project Predacon?
您的结论最为合乎逻辑 我的君王
Your conclusion is most logical, my liege.
万一我们的背叛让那个喷火的兽人发觉了怎么办？
But what happens if that fire-breathing brute discovers our treachery?
干嘛非要认为我们得亲自动手呢？
Why assume that we will be the ones to perform the deed?
毕竟 比如说 如果冲云霄发现是汽车人干掉了他的战友的话
After all, if the Predaking were to discover that, say, the Autobots were responsible for wiping out his comrades
我们手里的这只野兽说不定\N会反过来消灭那些我们所痛恨的敌人…
Our resident beast might, in turn, destroy our hated enemies for us...
…或是被消灭
or they him.
通天晓
Ultra Magnus.
你有烦心事了吧
Something has been troubling you.
我担心我的领导方式给部下的士气带来了负面影响
I fear that my command style may be having a negative effect on unit morale.
你是最忠于职守的 老朋友
Your service is most welcome, old friend.
但这里毕竟不是精英卫队
But this is not the Elite Guard.
塞博特恩之战后很多事情都发生了变化
Things have changed since the War for Cybertron.
而我们必须适应这种变化
And we must adapt to that change.
领袖卫队的成员并不只是一部机器中的齿轮
The members of Team Prime are not cogs in a machine.
他们已经获得了一种比军人更重要的身份
They've grown into something greater than an army.
他们已经成为…
They have become...
擎天柱 扫描装置探测到了露天能量矿
Optimus, our scanners have detected exposed energon.
鉴于我们的储备严重不足
With our reserves at a critical low
我们不能再放弃调查了
we cannot afford not to investigate.
霸天虎们 放下能量 立即投降
Decepticons, step away from the energon and surrender.
嘿呀！
Hia!
瞧瞧这些甜美的燃料
Look at all that sweet fuel.
潜行小队 把货物运送回基地
Stealth Team, transport our cargo back to base.
雷霆救援队 侦查矿脉
Wreckers, reconnoiter the mine.
我一直想跟雷霆救援队一起行动…
I've always wanted to roll with the Wreckers...
嗯…长官
Uh... Sir.
没有能量信号
No energon signals.
也没有加强戒备
And no additional security.
看起来很不对劲
Something doesn't smell right.
两两一组
Pair off.
好吧 这是丑八怪展览馆么
Well, this is one whole lot of ugly.
看来威震天的克隆计划比我们预期的要更快
Megatron's cloning operation seems further along than we anticipated.
红蜘蛛 汽车人来了
Starscream, the Autobots have arrived.
你没通知我 计划已经开始执行了
You did not inform me that your plan was already in motion.
假戏只有这样演才能…更乱真嘛
Only so the whole affair would appear less... staged.
我还没完全清除实验室的敏感数据
I have yet to purge my lab of sensitive materials.
那你就快抓紧吧 震荡波 通话完毕
Then do not let me keep you, Shockwave. Over and out.
你其实是想整他 是吧？
You scrapped him on purpose, didn't you?
声波 我需要紧急开启环陆桥
Soundwave, I require an immediate ground bridge.
威震天陛下 看来巨狰狞计划已经落入汽车人手里了
Lord Megatron, it seems Project Predacon has fallen into Autobot's hands.
这怎么可能？！
How was this possible!?
红蜘蛛 紧急出动你的追踪者大军
Starscream, scramble your seeker and armada.
这就去 我的君王
At once, my liege.
不！
No!
如果我的弟兄们受到威胁 就该由我去直面敌人
If my brethren are imperiled, I will confront the enemy.
请求批准在密闭空间扔颗手雷 长官？
Permission to employ a grenade in a confined space, Sir?
如果只有我们两个能阻止 这些野兽屠戮这颗星球上的居民
If you and I are all that stand between these monsters and the natives of this planet
那么 只管动手 把这些野兽轰成渣
then, by all means, blow these beasts back to the rust age.
这家伙是谁？
Who's this guy?
就是之前曾放你一马的那个
The very same who has previously allowed you to live
不过这次可没门
But will not today.
他是那只巨狰狞
He is the Pradecon.
哇喔！怎么回事？
Wow! What was that?
你们对我的兄弟做了什么？！
What have you done to my brethren!?
你们究竟做了什么？！
What have you done!?
呀！
Yah!
呃…那好吧 我们耍一耍！
Umh... Well then, let's dance!
喔！
Woh!
呃！
Eh!
啊！哦！
Ah!... Oh!...
啊！！
Aah!!
啊！！！
Aah!!!
嗯呃…
Uhm... eh...
呃！
Eh!...
唉…我刚刚开始能忍受你
Eh... and here, I was just beginning to tolerate you.
和你一起共事是我的荣幸 士兵
It's been an honor serving beside you, soldier.
准备受死吧
Prepare to perish.
啊！
Awh!!!
什么？！不！！！
What!? No!!!
噢…
Oh...
救护车会好好照顾你的
Ratchet will take good care of you.
老通打架满有救援队范儿的
Magnus fought like a wrecker.
擎天柱 我们之前谈到过
Optimus, when we spoke earlier.
比军人更重要的身份是什么？
What could be greater than an army?
一个人类发明的词汇
A human concept.
这是我来到地球之后才懂得的…
one I have learned since coming to Earth...
家人
Family.
不要绝望嘛 冲云霄
Do not despair, my Predaking.
我向你保证…
For I vow to you...
…汽车人会为对你族群的恶行付出沉重代价的
that the Autobots will pay dearly for the outrage against your kind.
震荡波 汇报
Shockwave, report.
已经确认 我的君王 巨狰狞计划已毁于一旦
It is true, my liege. Project Predacon has been rendered null and void.
我已经无法再复活任何野兽个体
At least, I have been unable to recover any beast-forms.
不过 有些东西需要您亲自过目
However, there is something you must behold for yourself.
哈！这又是什么东东？
Heh! What is this?
纯正的塞博特恩网状物质
Pure Cybertronian cybermatter
与曾存在于我们家园的同类物质非常相似
not unlike that which once existed upon our primeval home world.
也就是说 与我在地球建造堡垒的材料非常相似
Or that which engendered my citadel here on Earth.
这是爆炸产生的？
The result of the explosion?
事实上 仅仅靠C.N.A.无法解释这种网状结构形成的原因
Indeed, yet the cybernucleic acid alone cannot account for these... cyber-forms.
所有符合逻辑的推断都指向了一个意外加入的因素…
All possible logic points to the presence of one unexpected variable...
合成能量
Synthetic Energon.